ILGWU. Carl Proper papers 5780/150
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Southeast, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  Newspaper clippings; memo to ILG president Mazur from exec. asst. James Parrott re suggested talking points for Atlanta, GA, staff meeting, July 22, 1989
- Upper South, 1983-1985 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  Reports to ILG president Sol Chaikin and General Executive Board from Upper South Department re negotiated contracts, anticipated difficulties, lack of work, 1983-85; newspaper clippings; newsletters, the Maiden-forum, Winter 1986, and the ILG'er Western District Council, November 1985; handwritten notes
- Negotiations (3 folders), 1991 (Box 3, Folder 27-29)
  Overview (schedule of opening negotiating sessions by local/industry association; policy guidelines; history of demands and settlements; associations (list of members); report of task force on contract language; consumer price index; benefit funds (health fund fact sheets); summary of demands; summary of negotiations; press release, "ILGWU and Major Dress and Coat Employer Groups Reach Accord on 3-Year Pacts for 35,000 Workers; Higher Wages, Increased Contributions to Health Plans, Funding to Strengthen Industry Called 'Pattern' for Northeast Outerwear"; draft of negotiation speech for Local 23-25 manager-secretary Edgar Romny
- Negotiations: Agreements, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  Agreements with New York Skirt and Sportswear Association, Metropolitan Area Apparel Association, Greater Blouse, Skirt & Undergarment Association, National Association of Blouse Manufacturers, National Women's Neckwear & Scarf Association, Sportswear Apparel Association, Industrial Association of Juvenile Apparel Manufacturers, Atlantic Apparel Contractors' Association, Association of Knitted Fabrics Manufacturers, Passementerie & Trimming Manufacturers Association; press releases
- Negotiations, 1970-1985 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  Statistics for outerwear contracts, 1970-85; newspaper clippings
- Negotiations, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Calendar of Collective Bargaining, New York State, 1987; press release, "ILGWU Negotiates Pacesetting Parental Leave," 1987; wage and price developments under 1985-88 industry agreement; collective agreement, Ladies' Apparel Contractors' Association and United Better Manufacturers Association with ILGWU and Dressmakers' Joint Council, 1985-88; United Rubber Workers collective bargaining policy, 1982
- Organizing Task Force (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Final report to the General Executive Board, 1987
- Payroll (Box 4, Folder 5)
  Financial records of salaries and reimbursements to officers
- Personnel: Policies, 1988-1990 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  Sexual harassment policy, 1990; memo on hiring freeze and restructuring, 1987; agreement with local 153, 1988
- Personnel: Co-op Education Program, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  Personnel records of participants in the NYC Cooperative Education Program (college interns, summer temporary staff)
- Presidents Office, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  Memos re restructuring; exec. v.p. Wilbur Daniels resume; procedures
- Mazur Correspondence: Association Appointments, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  Letters noting appointment of ILGWU president Mazur to boards of other organizations: AFL-CIO committees, the Atlantic Council, Committee for National Health Insurance, Council on Foreign Relations, Fashion Institute of Technology, National Committee on Pay Equity, National Planning Association
- Mazur Correspondence, 1986-1992 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  Memos and letters to and from ILGWU president Mazur
- Resolutions, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  1992 Convention policy statements
- Resolutions, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  1989 Convention policy statements
- Resolutions to AFL-CIO, 1987-1989 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  Resolutions submitted by ILGWU to AFL-CIO or Industrial Union Department conventions; drafts and memo re AIDS resolution, noting need to consult with health care unions, Sept. 21, 1987
- Speeches, 1983-1988 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  Speeches by ILGWU presidents Jay Mazur (Columbia University School of Social Work, 1986; Hofstra University, 1988; NYS Council of Senior Citizens, 1988; Social Democrats USA, 1987; Congressional Research Service, 1987) and Sol Chaikin on trade/globalization, minimum wage, and other economic issues
- Speeches, 1988-1990 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  Correspondence and notes for speeches to the Atlantic Apparel Contractors Association, September 1989; New York Skirt and Sportswear, October 20, 1988; ACTWU Convention, 1990
- II. Subject Files (Box 4, Folder 15a)
- A. Apparel Industry (Box 4, Folder 15b)
  see also "New York City Apparel Industry," "New York State Apparel Industry," and "ILGWU Apparel Industry"
- Apparel Industry: Articles, 1984-1988 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  Newspaper, trade, and scholarly journal articles re economics, fashion, manufacturing. New Yorker Annals of Business: "The Sweater Trade," January 18, 1988; special issue of the Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science, "Deindustrialization: Restructuring the Economy," September 1984; Business Week special report, "The Hollow Corporation," March 3, 1986; ILGWU Research Department, "Conditions in the Women's Garment Industry," November 30, 1988; article, "Leading Virginia Industries: Textiles and Apparel: A Business Update, 1986" Robert W. Haigh and Donald W. Lindsey, Colgate Darden Graduate School of Business Administration
- Apparel Industry: Fact Sheets, 1973-1991 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  Descriptions and statistics re ILGWU, apparel industry, New York City, states, trade, CAF/GIDC, AFL-CIO, economic issues, income distribution
- Apparel Industry: Statistics, 1958-1986 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  U.S. Bureau of Census statistics of number and type of establishment, number of workers by occupation; narrative, Geographic Distribution of Apparel Employment; article, "The U.S. Apparel Industry, 1960-1985, with Special Emphasis on Women's and Children's Apparel," Research Dept. ILGWU, October 18, 1985
- Apparel Industry: Statistics on Conditions, Employment, Imports, Production, 1972-1988 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Apparel Industry: Statistics on States, Prices, Worker Characteristics, 1973-1986 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Apparel Industry: Workforce Statistics 1980 Census, 1960-1970 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Demographic characteristics of the apparel industry workforce (educational attainment, race, sex, age); comparison with 1970 and 1960
- Apparel Industry: Trade Associations, 1989-1992 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Members lists (with addresses, number of employees) for Apparel Manufacturers Association; Association of Rain Apparel Contractors, Inc.; Atlantic Apparel Contractors Association; the Belt Association; Fashion Apparel Manufacturers Association; Industrial Association of Juvenile Apparel Manufacturers; Infants, Children's Girls Wear Association; Knitted Outerwear Manufacturers Association; National Association of Blouse Manufacturers; New York Coat and Suit Association; New York Raincoat Manufacturers Association; New York Skirt and Sportswear Association; Northeast Apparel Contractors' Association; Philadelphia Apparel Manufacturers Association; United Knitwear Manufacturers League
- B. Articles (Box 5, Folder 4a)
  see also under subject headings (apparel, trade, sweatshops, etc.)
- Newspaper, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Clippings re the economy, role and perception of unionism; Journal of State Government, January/February 1987 re labor-management relations
- Scholarly: A-I, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Includes: Albelda, Randy, with June Lapidus, "Women and Children Last," The Economic Report of the People, Center for Popular Economics, Boston, MA, edited ms., c. 1985
- Scholarly: K-Q, 1982-1988 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Includes: Kahn, Shulamit, "Trends in Union Membership in the Postwar Period: The Case of the ILGWU," University of California, Irvine, December 1985; Kassalow, Everett M., "The Future of American Unionism: A Comparative Perspective," Annals, AAPSS 473, May 1984, and "Concession Bargaining Something Old, But Also Something Quite New," Proceedings of the 35th Annual Meeting of IRRA, 1982; Mort, Jo-Ann, "The Return of the Sweatshop," Dissent (Democratic Socialists of America), Summer 1988
- Scholarly: R-Z, 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Includes: Sabel, Charles F., "Studied Trust: Building New Forms of Cooperation in a Volitile Economy," presented at the T.E.P. Conference, Cite des Sciences et de l'Industrie, June 24-27, 1990; Wilkins, Jr., Bruce, "The ILGWU's Approach to Strategic Planning with the New York Garment Industry," unpublished paper, June 12, 1991
- Scholarly: Bonacich, Edna, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Sociologist at University of California, Riverside. List of researchers worldwide studying the garment industry, with cover letter from Bonacich suggesting starting an international interest group and convening a conference (n.d.); cover letter to ILG exec. asst. James Parrott asking for comment on several papers: first draft, "The Swimwear Sector of the Los Angeles Garment Industry"; first draft, "The Restructuring of the Pacific Rim Garment Industry: A Perspective from the United States," coauthored with David Waller; "The Flow of Capital, Labor and Trade in the Pacific Rim Garment Industry"; "The Current Fiber Type Overseas Investment," Korean Fiber Industry Association, October 1990; "Informacion Sobre las Actividad Maquiladora del Vestido en Mexico," Jorge Carrillo, Departmento de Estudios Sociales el Colegio de la Frontera Norte (in Spanish), presented at a UCLA conference on the Pacific Rim garment industry, November 29-30, 1990; program agenda
- Scholarly: Parsons, Carol, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  Assistant professor, urban and regional planning, University of Iowa. Unpublished papers: "Immigration and Regional Labor Market Dynamics in the U.S. Apparel Industry: A Research Proposal to the Immigration Policy Group, International Labor Affairs Bureau, U.S. Dept. of Labor"; "The Future of the Domestic Apparel Industry," hand-annotated briefing paper for the Center for Labor-Management Policy Studies, CUNY; "Technological Innovation and Industrial Location: A Political Economy Approach," presented at the American Collegiate Schools of Planning meeting, Nov. 5-9, 1987
- Scholarly: Piore, Michael J., 1979-1985 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  Economics professor and Mitsui Professor of Problems of Contemporary Technology at MIT; "Can Labor Survive Re-Gomperization?" paper presented to Industrial Relations Research Association, Dec. 28, 1982; Piore and Thomas Bacley, draft, "Defending the Minimum Wage: Memorandum prepared for the ILGWU," Sept. 1979; excerpts from and articles about The Second Industrial Divide: Possibilities for Prosperity, and several other articles (published); handwritten notes
- Scholarly: Rosen, Ellen, 1989-1991 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  Sociology professor, Nichols College, visiting professor, Harvard and MIT Sloan School of Management; unpublished papers, some with hand annotations, on men's tailored clothing industry; women and the future of American manufacturing; survey of job-leavers in the needle trades; case study on technology innovation in the U.S. apparel industry; comments on study by reviewers; researcher's vita
- Scholarly: Tyler, Gus, 1985-1990 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  Published and unpublished papers and correspondence by (and about) the ILGWU official and activist re trade policy, minimum wage, political figures.
- Scholarly: Zeitlin, Jonathan, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  Published paper coauthored with Peter Toterdill; handwritten and typed notes from talk, Dec. 1988
- Blacks, 1978-1990 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  Paper presented at the annual meeting of the Association for the Study of Afro- American Life and History, Inc., Oct. 19, 1984: "Some Exploratory Notes on Black Election and Appointment to Union Office: The Ignored Democratic Revolution," by Everette J. Freeman, assistant professor of labor studies at Rutgers University, with cover letter to ILG Research Department inviting comments; printed booklet: Black Initiative and Governmental Responsibility, with introduction by John Hope Franklin and Eleanor Holmes Norton, an essay by the Committee on Policy for Racial Justice, published by the Joint Center for Political Studies, 1987; newspaper article about the report; First Friday Report: "Black Unemployment: Just How Serious Is It?" issued by National Committee for Full Employment and the National Urban League in conjunction with AFL-CIO and several others, August 1, 1986; course guide for class, "Black People in the American Labor Force," ACTWU NTRTP, 1981; AFL-CIO American Federationist reprint, "Black Workers: Progress Derailed," by Barbara Becnel, 1978; book review by ILG official Gus Tyler, Oct. 17, 1990; newspaper clippings
- Catholic Bishops pastoral on the Economy, 1984-1986 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  Full text of first draft, November 15, 1984; full text of final letter, "Economic Justice for All: Pastoral Letter on Catholic Social Teaching and the U.S. Economy," National Conference of Catholic Bishops, November 27, 1986; statements and press releases by AFL-CIO in support of letter; testimony before the U.S. House Subcommittee on Economic Stabilization, March 19, 1985, in support of first draft: by Nobel laureate economist James Tobin, "Running the Economy with Less Unemployment and Poverty"; by Nobel laureate economist Lawrence Klein, "On the Possibility of Reducing Unemployment and Poverty in a Non-inflationary Growth Economy"; and by three other economists, Robert Eisner, Northwestern University; Isabel Sawhill, Urban Institute, "Unemployment and Poverty: Can We Do Better?"; and Nancy Barrett, American University, "Achieving Full Employment"; newsletter from National Committee for Full Employment, December 11, 1986, "Jobs Impact"; newspaper clippings
- Catholic Conference, U.S., 1981 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  Text of 1891 encyclical by Pope Leo XIII, "On the Condition of Workers: Rerum Novarum"; text of 1981 third encyclical letter by Pope John Paul II, "On Human Work: Laborum Exercens"; catalog of publications available
- Child Care, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  Comments by ILG vp Susan Cowell to director of NYS Division for Women re attached proposal, "Feasibility of a Public-Private Partnership for Child Care in New York State"
- Child Labor, 1978-1992 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  Testimony by ILG president Jay Mazur before House Committee on Government Operations, Subcommittee on Employment and Housing, re violations of child labor laws, Mar. 23, 1990; testimony by General Accounting Office (GAO) director of Education and Employment Issues, Human Resources Division, re child labor law violations and sweatshops, March 16, 1990; testimony to U.S. Department of Labor Hearings on Industrial Homework in the Women's Apparel Industry by several individuals who performed industrial homework, March 1989; testimony by ILG exec. v.p. Edgar Romney in support of strengthening child labor laws in New York State, February 7, 1990, with cover letter from vp Susan Cowell summarizing highlights; testimony by ILG vp Barbara Laufman at New York State Department of Labor hearings on child labor laws, July 27, 1988; letter from NYS Commissioner of Labor re proposed changes to New York State child labor laws, with press release re intent to hold hearings, June 1988; letter from ILG vp Susan Cowell to Commissioner re need to retain current prohibition against factory work for 14- and 15-year-olds, December 9, 1988; testimony by Mazur in support of the Child Labor Exploitation Prevention Act of 1987 before the House Ways and Means Committee, August 19, 1988; testimony by AFL-CIO secretary-treasurer Thomas Donahue before Subcommittee on Labor Standards of the House Committee on Education and Labor re Department of Labor proposals to relax child labor lows, July 28, 1982; legislative history of child labor provisions of the Fair Labor Standards Act, complied by AFL-CIO, August 2, 1982; AFL-CIO memo/notes on House hearings on child labor laws, Aug. 3, 1982; New York State Department of Labor News press release re fines for child labor law violations, July 23, 1991; GAO publications: "Child Labor: Increases in Detected Child Labor Violations throughout the United States," prepared for Rep. Don Pease, April 1990; "Child Labor: Information on Federal Enforcement Efforts," June 1992; U.S. Dept. of Labor publication: "Child Labor Requirements in Nonagricultural Occupations under the Fair Labor Standards Act," revised July 1978; newspaper clippings
- Clinton Presidential Campaign, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  "Solidarity" comic book in the style of Dr. Seuss, "The Outrageous Adventures of George & Dan" (Bush and Quayle), September 1992; drafts of policy papers for transition team re industrial development policy; press releases from Clinton/Gore campaign re manufacturing, technology; newspaper clippings
- Compensation and Executive Pay, 1988-1993 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  Clipping from Apparel Industry Magazine, "Alternative Ways to Pay Your Employees," August 1992; memo to ILG president Mazur re attached article from Business Week, noting executive pay rose 48% in 1987, while pay for top labor leaders was largely unchanged, April 26, 1988; "Top Corporate Executives Take 56% Pay Hike, Workers Struggle to Keep Up With Inflation" AFL-CIO News, May 3, 1993; "Labor Costs From Pakistan to Portugal," Bobbin, September 1992; newspaper clippings. See also "Poverty/Income Distribution"
- Employee Ownership (2 folders), 1989 (Box 6, Folder 4-5)
  Articles and publications on Employee Stock Ownership Plans (ESOPs); handwritten notes by Jay Mazur, "ESOP Study Group"; letter to Mazur from ACTWU president Jack Sheinkman re draft proposal for a Union/Employee Buyout Fund, with attached proposal, noting upcoming meeting of the AFL-CIO Industrial Union Department Pension and Benefit Fund Policy Committee, Feb. 6, 1989; letter to Mazur from Omak Wood Products, Omak, WA, re recent employee acquisition of the company, February 13, 1989. see also New York (State) Center for Employee Ownership and Participation
- HMOs, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  Newsletters for health maintenance organizations, Managed Health Care, July 17, 1989, and Health Week, July 17, 1989
- Homework (2 folders), 1941-1990 (Box 6, Folder 7-8)
  "Aspects of Industrial Homework in the Apparel Trades," 1941, Teper and Weinberg, ILGWU Research Department; Industrial Homework Fact Sheet and chronology of Department of Labor regulatory actions, 1989; speech by Mazur, "Industrial Homework and Sweatshops," to the National Association of Governmental Labor Organizations, July 20, 1987; article/speech by Evelyn Dubrow, ILG vp and legislative director, "Women and Industrial Homework"; press release, "ILG Will Sue To Keep Prohibition against Industrial Homework," Sept. 26, 1989; court decision re lawsuit by ILGWU against U.S. Labor Secretary Elizabeth Dole et al., for rescinding the ban on industrial homework, December 7, 1989; court decision for similar suit, November 29, 1983; letter to the editor by Mazur, and another by chairman of House Subcommittee on Labor Standards, responding to article in New York Times re homework, March 23, 1987; editorial by Mazur in New York Times, "Back to the Sweatshop," September 6, 1986; memo from ILG criticizing attached article from Ms, "Is Homework the Answer?" August 25, 1987; Federal Register printed proposal to rescind ban on homework, December 30, 1988; Written Statement of M. Patricia Fernandez Kelly (associate professor, Johns Hopkins) in Response to Advance Notice of Rulemaking and Notice of Hearing Respecting Employment of Homeworkers in the Apparel Industry, Department of Labor, March 9, 1989; Statement of Homeworkers about Their Experiences, prepared by ILGWU; press release by Rep. Major Owens opposing Department of Labor's rescinding ban on homework; papers prepared for a conference, "The New Era of Homework: Directions and Responsibilities," cosponsored by the Graduate School of the City University of New York and the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services, Feb. 1-3, 1987: "Home-based Work and Technological and Economic Trends, Office of Technology Assessment, U.S. Congress," "Protection of Clerical Homeworkers: From What, By Whom?" by Congressman Barney Frank's office, "Homework in the Past: Its Meaning for the Future," Eileen Boris, Howard University, "Home-work: What is it and Who does it?" Bell Communications Network; report for National Commission on Working Women, "Homework: Employment Option or Employment Risk?" 1985; report by ILG vp Susan Cowell on the International Labour Organization Meeting of Experts on the Social Protection of Homeworkers, with draft conclusions, Geneva, October 1-5, 1990; copies of published articles, newspaper clippings
- Homework (2 folders), 1988 (Box 6, Folder 9-10)
  Statements, memos, and press releases by ILGWU in response to ruling by Reagan administration's Dept. of Labor allowing homework in selected apparel-related industries; press release from NYS Dept. of Labor, opposing ruling; ILGWU brochure, Questions & Answers on Industrial Homework; contract with CUNY professor Roger Waldinger to provide analysis of census data comparing homeworkers with non- homeworkers; newspaper clippings
- C. Immigration (Box 6, Folder 9a)
- Undocumented Aliens, 1981-1986 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  "U.S. Immigration Policy and the National Interest," executive summary of the final report of the Select Commission on Immigration and Refugee Policy, March 1, 1981, submitted to Congress and the President of the United States pursuant to Public Law 95-412; teacher's guide, "Immigrants: The Back Bone of America," Karin J. Gerstel, ACTWU-NTRPT, 1981; research report, "Illegal Immigration: U.S. Economic and Labor Market Impacts," by Robert G. Ainsworth, National Commission for Employment Policy, April 1983; Rand report, "Current and Future Effects of Mexican Immigration in California," executive summery, Kevin F. McCarthy, R. Burciaga Valdez, November 1985; report supported by Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, "Legalization of Undocumented Aliens: Lessons from Other Countries," by Doris Meissner and Demetrios G. Papademetriou, December 10, 1986; Center for Immigration Studies press release, "Future Joblessness in Mexico and Caribbean Will Sharply Boost Immigration Pressures," November 20, 1986; International Migration Review articles: "Geographic Distribution of Undocumented Immigrants: Estimates of Undocumented Aliens Counted in the 1980 Census by State," by Jeffrey S. Passel and Karen A. Woodrow, Population Division, U.S. Bureau of the Censes, fall 1984; special issue, "Women In Migration," winter 1984; Time special immigration issue, July 8, 1985; American Demographics article, "The Illegals," by Courtenay Slater, January 1985; Journal of the Institute for Socioeconomic Studies article, "How Many Illegal Aliens?" by Courtenay Slater, winter 1986; Economic Review article, "Enforcing Sanctions against Employers of Illegal Aliens," by John K. Hill, senior economist, Federal Reserve Bank of Dallas, and James E. Pearce, vice president, Federal Home Loan Bank of Atlanta, May 1987; Annals, AAPSS, "Undocumented Immigration," by Jeffrey S. Passel, September 1986; Monthly Labor Review, "Estimating the Number of Undocumented Aliens," by Jeffrey Passel, September 1986; newspaper clippings
- Immigration Reform and Control Act of 1986 (IRCA), 1988-1992 (Box 6, Folder 12)